So, now the question is,
现在的问题是
what do we do when our data is not normally distributed?
如果数据不是正态分布 该怎么办？
Similarly, what do we do when our data is heteroscedastic?
或者 如果数据具有异方差性 该怎么办？
To reshape our data and make it more normal,
要变形数据 使其更正态
we can feed our data into the log function.
我们可以将数据传入对数函数中
To get data that is homoscedastic,
要使数据具有同方差性
we can take the time difference between periods.
我们可以计算时期之间的时间差
By time difference, I mean that we can view
时间差是指
our data as the rate of return from one day to the next.
将数据看做两天之间的收益率
Similarly, we could get the time difference by
同理 我们可以用当天的值
subtracting each previous day's value from the current day's value.
减去前一天的值得出时间差
In practice, we take the rate of change for each period and then apply the log function.
在实践中 我们计算出每个时间间隔的变化率 然后应用对数函数
You may have seen this earlier when learning about why we
之前学习为何用对数收益率对金融数据进行建模时
model financial data with log returns.
已经提到过这种对数方式
A way to make our data both normally distributed and homoscedastic,
使数据同时保持正态分布和同方差性的一种方式是
is by applying the Box-Cox transformation.
应用 Box-Cox 变换
To preview what the Box-Cox transformation does,
在了解 Box-Cox 变换的作用之前
let's get a conceptual idea of what a transformation looks like.
先来了解下什么是变换
Imagine you place all your data points on a number line,
假设所有数据点都在一个数值轴上
they are not evenly spaced and have odd clusters in
数据点分布不均匀 某些部分聚集了一些点
some parts and no data points in other places.
某些部分没有数据点
Think of this as a necklace in which the beads are not spaced out in a very nice way.
可以想象成一条项链 珠子分布得并不均匀
Now, imagine if we could nudge each of these beads a little bit to
假设我们能够左右挪动每个珠子
the left and to the right to even out the spacing in a nicer way.
使它们之间的间隔一样
Notice that since these beads are all on the same string,
因为所有珠子都在一条线上
the relative order of each data point remains the same,
所以每个数据点之间的相对顺序不变
we're just spacing them out in a way that's easier to work with.
只是调整它们之间的间隔 便于处理
In math terms, we just applied a monotonic transformation.
用数学术语来说 我们应用了单调变换
A monotonic transformation changes the values of
单调变换会改变数据集的值
a dataset but preserves the relative order.
但是保持相对顺序
The Box-Cox transformation takes a dataset
Box-Cox 变换会将数据集变成
and outputs a dataset that is more normally distributed.
更加正态分布的数据集
You can see that the Box-Cox transformation has one constant value, lambda.
Box-Cox 变换有一个常量值 λ
If you choose lambda to be zero,
如果将 λ 设为 0
then the transformation function is defined as the natural log.
那么该变换函数就是自然对数
You can try different values for lambda to transform the data,
你可以尝试将 λ 设为不同的值
then perform tests for normality and homoscedasticity.
然后检验正态性和方差齐性
Once you can say your data is normally distributed,
数据正态分布后
you can use it in the various models that we'll discuss in the rest of the lesson.
就可以将其用在这节课的后续部分讨论的各种模型中了